Hi, my name is Windy St. George, and this is how to play twenty questions. Twenty questions is a simple parlor game that you can use to pass the time.
You don't need any props.
One person thinks of a, of an object or an item that they're thinking of, and the other person gets twenty questions to guess what it would be.
So, why don't you think of something, okay.
Okay, you usually start off by asking general questions that'll help you narrow it down.
Is it; you can only ask yes or no questions, very important.
Is it an animal?
Yes.
Okay, is it bigger than a breadbox?
No.
Is it a carnivore?
Yes.
Does it say meow?
No.
Is it kept as a pet normally?
Okay, is it ever kept as a pet?
No.
Is it found in a circus?
Is it found in a zoo?
Yes.
We're supposed to be counting questions.
You're supposed to count until twenty, yeah.
When you play twenty questions there are typical questions that you ask that'll help you narrow down quickly what the item is.
Usually, is it an animal, a vegetable, or a mineral, or an idea, and you have to get a yes or no for each one of those.
Once you narrow that down you ask about its size.
Usually is it bigger than a breadbox, and so forth until you've got a rough idea of the size.
For animals you should ask what does it eat?
Is it a vegetarian or a meat eater, if it flies or if it swims, and general questions like this; if it has fur, if it's warm blooded or cold blooded will help you narrow down until you can, hopefully, guess what the object is before your twenty questions are up.
And that's how you play twenty questions.